<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: backbone.js | Ruemic's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://ruemic.github.com/blog/categories/backbone-js/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ruemic.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-17T20:46:52+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://ruemic.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Ruescher]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rails, Backbone, Coffeescript, Github, Oh My!]]></title>
    <link href="http://ruemic.github.com/blog/2012/09/17/rails/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-17T15:02:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://ruemic.github.com/blog/2012/09/17/rails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I'm currently doing front end development with the awesome team at <a href="http://www.bigbadgoose.com/">Big Bad Goose</a> to create the <a href="http://www.goodies.co">Goodies</a> food discovery app for Walmart Labs.</p>

<p>It's the first time I've had the privilege of working on a production web application running Ruby on Rails, backbone.js and using GitHub for source control. I've learned a ton, so here's a little digest of each technology.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h4>CoffeeScript</h4>

<p>The javascript portion of the app is  written entirely in CoffeeScript, which is a dialect of javascript that gets rid of a lot of ugly syntax and only uses the "good parts" of the language.</p>

<p>I've really taken a liking to CoffeeScript because it lets you focus on the logic of the behavior or interaction you're attempting to define instead of forcing you to nitpick the syntax of javascript.</p>

<p>Since I'm working on the front end, I'm mostly just using a lot of jQuery to write functions for event handlers to make things interactive. The CoffeeScript for each page is contained within a custom backbone.js view class which has a module for binding and triggering custom named events. This combination using backbone to organize the code and writing the functions in jQuery and CoffeeScript makes for really expressive code.</p>

<h5>More on Backbone and Ruby on Rails coming soon!</h5>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
