<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Ruemic's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://ruemic.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ruemic.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-09-17T18:11:20+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://ruemic.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Michael Ruescher]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Rails, Backbone, Coffeescript, Github, Oh My!]]></title>
    <link href="http://ruemic.github.com/blog/2012/09/17/rails/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-17T15:02:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://ruemic.github.com/blog/2012/09/17/rails</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m currently doing front end development with the awesome team at <a href="http://www.bigbadgoose.com/">Big Bad Goose</a> to create the <a href="http://www.goodies.co">Goodies</a> food discovery app for Walmart Labs.</p>

<p>It&#8217;s the first time I&#8217;ve had the privilege of working on full fledged web application running Ruby on Rails, backbone.js and using GitHub for source control. I&#8217;ve learned a ton, so here&#8217;s a little digest of each technology.</p>

<!-- more -->


<h4>CoffeeScript</h4>

<p>The app is entirely written in CoffeeScript, which is a dialect of javascript that gets rid of a lot of ugly syntax and only uses the &#8220;good parts&#8221; of the javascript language.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve really taken a liking to CoffeeScript because it lets you focus on the logic the behavior or interactive you&#8217;re attempting to define instead of forcing you yo nitpick at your syntax.</p>

<p>Since I&#8217;m purely on the front end, I&#8217;m mostly just using a lot of jQuery to write functions for event handlers to make things interactive. The combination of jQuery and CoffeeScript makes for really expressive code and I look forward to do a lot more with it.</p>

<h5>Backbone, Ruby on Rails coming soon!</h5>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Upgrading the Blog]]></title>
    <link href="http://ruemic.github.com/blog/2012/09/05/Upgrading-the-Blog/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-05T02:10:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://ruemic.github.com/blog/2012/09/05/Upgrading-the-Blog</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>Because if it ain&#8217;t fun, it won&#8217;t get done</h3>

<p>I created this blog to reflect on my journey to become a coder/designer. It is also a place for me to experiment with code and design. Although I&#8217;ve customized several Wordpress sites before, I decided I wanted to try something new and more lightweight.</p>

<p>I started out by simply hand coding the html for each post. Turns out that was way too much overhead, and posting felt like work instead of being fun. So it simply didn&#8217;t get done. I needed to streamline my authoring flow. Enter <a href="http://octopress.org/docs/">Octopress</a>.</p>

<!--More-->


<p>Lucky for me, some really smart folks have come up with a much better way to blog. Octopress iss a framework for <a href="http://jekyllrb.com/">Jekyll</a>, which is a &#8220;blog aware static site generator&#8221; written in Ruby.</p>

<p>It makes it really quick and easy to post, but also keeps things close to the metal in terms of the authoring tools. Octopress is set up to run on github pages so all you have to do is write a post in <a href="http://daringfireball.net/projects/markdown/">Markdown</a>, generate the static html site, and deploy it. It looks a little something like this:</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>$ rake generate</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>(It comes with Solarized code highlighting!)</p>

<figure class='code'><div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>$ rake deploy</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure>


<p>This pushes your latest changes to github, which then automatically deploys via <a href="http://pages.github.com/">Github Pages</a>.</p>

<p>So that means you also automatically get the added benefit of being on version control, so if you want to branch off with an experiment, manage to really screw something up, or want to collaborate with other authors, you have github to manage that process.</p>

<p>I&#8217;m looking forward to get to know Octopress better, and actually blogging while at it!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Really ain't too much different]]></title>
    <link href="http://ruemic.github.com/blog/2012/07/13/globetrotting/"/>
    <updated>2012-07-13T14:39:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://ruemic.github.com/blog/2012/07/13/globetrotting</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>One of the best things about being a freelancer is the freedom to pick projects that allow for a flexible work schedule and working remotely. It&#8217;s allowed me to keep designing and building web sites as I travel the world with my beautiful wife to visit our extended family.</p>

<p>I&#8217;ve been in Hong Kong for about a month now, and one thing I notice as I ride the subway is that the amount of smart-phone and tablet usage seems even higher here than back home in Silicon Valley.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Even in mainland China, where incomes are lower than in Hong Kong, about 50% of the people on the subway are on a smart-phone or tablet. There are plenty of iPhones, but Android is the most prevalent. I saw a fully capable Nexus 3 knockoff for under $100 USD.</p>

<p>I think that for many in China, this is their main and most capable PC.</p>

<p>I recently finished the Steve jobs biography, and there is a really interesting anecdote from when Steve goes to Turkey, and a tour guide is going on about how special the Turkish coffee is, the ingredients, the roasting process&#8230;</p>

<p>While Steve is listening to this he&#8217;s also kind of zoning out and realizes that no one in Turkey really cares about their coffee! And he notices that all the young folks have smart phones and are wearing jeans and T-shirts.</p>

<p>He comes to the conclusion that for young people everywhere, there is no longer a Turkish culture or German culture or a US culture, there is only one world culture.</p>

<p>In a general sense, I agree with him. Living in China just confirms to me what I&#8217;ve felt since I was a very young kid when my family immigrated to the US from Austria. While I was growing up, I&#8217;d visit Austria for a month or two during my Summer break, and I had this epiphany that contrary some of the beliefs of my schoolmates in the US, people are quite similar in Europe and the US. Now, at least when it comes to the younger &amp; more tech savvy generation, I&#8217;m adding China to the list.</p>

<p>To me, the implication is that there is a universal archetype of what appeals to people. So as designer it&#8217;s my job to be attuned to that, and to actively impart it upon my work. There&#8217;s no magic to it, like anything else, it&#8217;s a discipline.</p>

<p>Half of it is cultivating a &#8220;minds eye&#8221; which actively observes the design fundamentals like shape, texture, color or proportions of my surroundings. The more I can do this, the more patterns I can log in my &#8220;library&#8221; of experiences to pull from for my designs.</p>

<p>But that&#8217;s the easy, quantitative part.</p>

<p>The other half is trickier, but vital context for making use of the first half. And that is: How does it make me feel? Even more important, how does this affect me at a subconscious level?</p>

<p>It&#8217;s tricky for several reasons. One is that the language of the subconscious is a superset of conscious thought, which is a superset of any spoken or written language, like English.</p>

<p>Attempting to observe and articulate a subconscious reaction to something tends to become an distorted expression of it. To manage this distortion, we must become poets, using metaphors like personification to evoke the original subconscious reaction.</p>

<p>For example, saying something like &#8220;That text is too crowded&#8221; takes the quantitative aspects (the spacing between words and letters) and connects it with a universal feeling of being in a crowded environment.</p>

<p>So a big part of being a good designer is having a rich collection of life experiences to tap into. Fully experiencing different cultures and languages is great way to build your sense of which metaphors and design patterns transcend our differences and universally appeal to all people.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Just Blog Already]]></title>
    <link href="http://ruemic.github.com/blog/2012/05/04/just-blog-already/"/>
    <updated>2012-05-04T15:29:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://ruemic.github.com/blog/2012/05/04/just-blog-already</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>A Note to Self</h3>

<p>There comes a time in life, where you just go for it. This is one of those times for me. The past three years of life since graduating from college have provided me many opportunities to try my hand at design. For this I am very grateful.</p>

<p>I always felt that when I was in &#8216;design mode&#8217; was when I created the most value, mostly because this is where I was the most passionate. I didn&#8217;t care if I had to spend several days of my own time learning something in order to bring an idea to life. It puts me in a state of &#8220;flow&#8221; and I once read that this is a very good thing.</p>

<!-- More -->


<p>So, that&#8217;s why I&#8217;ve now decided to be a web designer full time. So far, it&#8217;s been a process of soaking up as much as I could, by gathering lots of input from blogs and various online classes like <a href="http://www.codeschool.com/">Codeschool</a>. And of course, by doing a lot of experimenting by building web sites!</p>

<p>To make viable a career of web design/development, I know need to be REALLY good. Which means I always need to keep learning and stay on top of ways the web as a whole is evolving, both technically and culturally. This blog is a way to summarize, perhaps on a weekly basis, the things I am learning, and why they matter.</p>

<p>If I can really get into the rhythm of publishing what I&#8217;m learning, then not only will it solidify my knowledge and abilities, but I will also be giving back to the community of designers and developers from whom I have learned most of what I know!</p>

<p>I hope this blog also serves as a way for potential clients or colleagues to get to know me. So you can get an idea of where my head&#8217;s at. Because design is about trust.</p>

<p>Often times when working out a design problem, I don&#8217;t know the answer yet. I might have a conception of what the outcome should be, but it&#8217;s still a bit fuzzy. That&#8217;s where trust is so important.</p>

<p>Any designer has to be allowed to try things and make mistakes to arrive at a good solution. So the process isn&#8217;t always pretty. Without trust, it can get pretty tough to make it to the other side.</p>

<p>So how does a client grant their trust to a designer? It&#8217;s only the future of their business thats on the line! It&#8217;s a really good question. But demonstrating good work and revealing my thought processes is part of the answer.</p>

<p>Good design is all about being able to put yourself in the shoes of the end user and creating an experience that is empathic to their wants and needs. This is the intangible part of the designers job, and it can involve a lot of convincing and cajoling of clients who may not see it that way.</p>

<p>So let this blog also serve as a way for potential clients to evaluate wether they would want me convincing and cajoling them!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
